有多少人订了DVD又不付钱的呢
Well, how many people have ordered DVDs and haven't pay for them.
要是
If...
我去学校的路上应该有时间绕一下的
I guess I could stop by my way to school.
非常非常重要的事
Really really important thing.
绮丽儿 我待会打给你
Cheryl? Can I call you back?
行 好的 再见
Okay. Great. Bye.
-好了 什么事 -那个
- Yes? What? - Hey, yeah...
我刚才仔细检查了浴室你的抽屉
I was going through your drawer in the bathroom
找一些唇膏什么的因为我的
looking for some lip stuff because my...
嘴唇干了
Lips were dry.
-天呐 你真了解我 -菲尔
- God, you know me. - Phil...
还记得我们在儿童医院拍到的
Remember the spa certificates we got
-温泉疗养券吗 -当然
- at the children's hospital auction? - Mm-hmm.
看看 明天就要到期了
Well, look at this -- they expire tomorrow.
那你要做什么
Oh, wow. What are you gonna do?
克莱尔 我觉得你没有意识到
Claire, I don't think you're grasping the magnitude
这一套服务的价值 这可值两百五十多美元呢
of this package, valued at over $250.
-亲爱的 -如果你不用它
- Sweetie... - If you don't use them,
那慈善机构就白拿我们的钱了
then all our money just goes to charity.
那我要怎么做
And so what am I supposed to do?
在管弦乐队放下艾丽克斯
Somewhere between dropping off Alex at orchestra
再照惯例去去接卢克
and picking up Luke from practice --
还烧制一堆才艺表演的DVD的日程之间
oh, and burning a bunch of dvds of the talent show,
难道我要跑去做个矿物盐磨砂
I'm gonna, what, pop in for a quick salt scrub?
我以为绮丽儿要烧制DVD呢
I thought Cheryl was doing the DVDs.
是的 本来是她
Well, she's supposed to,
但她就是把这活塞给我了
but somehow she's got me doing it.
你应该这样说
Here's what you do.
就说 绮丽儿今天我不行
Say, "Cheryl, no can do today.
我需要一点属于自己的时间
Need a little 'me time.'"
你见过绮丽儿吗
Have you met Cheryl?
那就会变成我的新绰号的
That'll be my new nickname.
就叫克莱尔·私人时间·邓菲
I'll be Claire "Me time" Dunphy.
这可太不划算了
It's not worth the headache.
那就说你病了
Just say you're sick.
然后万一我突然撞见她了 那不就彻底穿帮了
Then I run into her, and it'll be a whole thing.
好吧 要是真那样的话
Well, if that happens,
你就说你去药店
you say you're on your way to the pharmacy to --
菲尔 亲爱的 行不通的
Phil, darling, no, not helping.
好吧 我送给同事弗洛伦斯·刚德曼
Fine. I'll give them to Florence Gunderman at work.
她每次弹班卓琴的时候我都能看见她龟裂的双手
Her hands look gross ever since she took up the banjo.
老妈 我要点钱吃午饭
Hey, mom, I need some money for lunch.
我们要去
We're all gonna go to --
天呐 把我的线衫脱下来
Oh, my god! Take off my sweater!
老妈 叫她脱下来
Mom, tell her to take it off!
艾丽克斯 脱下来
Alex, take it off.
上周 她问都没问就穿了我的运动衫
Last week, she wore my sweatshirt without asking.
没错
That is true.
拜托 那可是抬举
Oh, please -- that was an honor
你的破运动衫
for your stupid old sweatshirt.
那是它第一次感受胸部的形状
It was the first time the top half got any exercise.
老妈 那是我最爱的线衫
Now, mom, that's my favorite sweater!
我刚买的
I just got it.
你们知道你们这些女生要学什么吗
You know what you girls need to learn to do?
你们要学会分享
You need to learn to share,
因为那才是姐妹该做的
because that's what sisters do.
行了海莉 你的线衫不会怎样的
All right, Haley, nothing's gonna happen to your sweater.
是吧 艾丽克斯
Right, alex?
是吧
Hmm?
行 行
Okay, fine.
那我就去穿件你最喜欢的书呆子T恤
Then I will just go put on your favorite nerdy T-shirt,
上面有"回到未来"的那件
The one with the guy from "back to the future" on it.
那是阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦
That's Albert Einstein!
而且一点也不书呆子气
And it is not nerdy!
好吧
Well...
你好啊
Hi!
老爸呀 农贸市场怎样呀
Hey, daddy. How was the farmers' market?
是不错 但猜猜 新品种菠菜是什么
Well, it was great, but guess what the new spinach is.
菊苣吗
Um, radicchio?
甘蓝
Kale.
不是吧
No!
我懂 我当时跟你一样凌乱
I know. I was just as blown away as you are.
好吧 我想我们要采用...
Oh, well, I guess we're going to have to adopt --
耶
yay --
新的态度看待甘蓝了
a new attitude towards kale.
可能也要用新的香料
Maybe we'll even adopt a new vinaigrette.
用起来用起来
Adopt, yay!
好啦 看看这里怎么啦
Okay, what's going on here?
我在运用收养的
I'm taking the negative charge
另一层含义 懂吗
out of the word "Adopted." Yay.
奥普拉这回又说什么了
What did Oprah do now?
这样的 她有个女儿
Well, she had a girl on
十六岁的时候发现自己是收养的
who, at 16, found out that she was adopted
她觉得被背叛就跑了 最后变成了脱衣舞女
and felt betrayed, ran away, and became a stripper --
还没在黄金地段 而是机场周边的那种
and not the heart-of-gol kind, the by-the-airport kind.
好
Okay.
行了 你尽情评论吧 朱迪法官
All right. Go get your gavel, Judge Judy.
不 完全不是 我接受了
No, not at all. I'm adopting
大人不计小人过
A tolerant attitude toward your flights of lunacy.
接受[还有领养的意思]
Adopting!
艾丽克斯 快点 快点
Alex, come on. Hurry up.
我们去的越迟
The later we are,
绮丽儿就会发短信叫我做更多的事
the more Cheryl texts me to do.
我来了 来了
I'm coming, I'm coming.
再跟我说说这小提琴为什么不跟你一样
Tell me again why the violin just wasn't you.
它太高兴了
It's too happy.
天呐
Oh, my god!
行了 别动别动别动
Okay, hang on. Hang on. Hang on.
我看看 应该没什么事
Let's see. It might not be a big deal.
来吧 我来看看
Just -- here we go. Let's see.
-好吧 -很糟吗
- Oh, okay. - Is it bad?
没事 没事的 你没事的
No, it's gonna be fine. You're gonna be okay.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
我忘带手机了
Hey, I forgot my phone.
你好啊
Hi.
干嘛啊
What?
没事 我爱你
Nothing. I love you.
古里古怪的
So weird.
你最好别溅什么东西在上面 知道吗 呆子
You better not spill anything on that, okay, dork?
放轻松 这毛衣结实着呢
Relax. Half the 11th grade's been inside this sweater.
更重要的是
More than anything
我希望我的女儿们不要吵架 亲近一点
I want my girls to stop fighting and be close.
我希望他们互相分享衣服 互相做发型
I want them to share clothes and do each other's hair
说说男孩子的绯闻
and gossip about boys --
就像以前我跟米奇尔那样
like I used to do with Mitchell.
歌洛莉亚 走吧 我们走吧
Gloria! Let's go, let's go, let's go!
杰 你有没有注意到我走路跳跃了一点
Hey, Jay, have you noticed a spring in my step?
童言无忌
Oh, kids say cruel things.
那也不代表你就是那样的
That doesn't mean you'll turn out that way.
不是 我们有相似之处
No. We have something in common.
我在和一位小美眉约会
I'm seeing a younger woman.
那是有多小
How much younger are we talking about?
十三个月 她叫克罗伊
13 months. Her name's Chloe.
她让我感觉自己又是五年级了
She makes me feel like a 5th grader again.
真替你开心 孩子
Good for you, kid.
都在啊 我的两个糟老头
Hmm. There they are -- my two dirty old men.
拜托 你很快就四十好几的人了
Hey, pretty soon you're gonna be north of 40
我都打算用个更靓的模特换掉你了
and I'm gonna have to trade you in for a newer model.
对不 兄弟
Am I right, buddy?
那是我老妈 杰
That's my mother, Jay.
准备好了吗
You ready?
这么好的天 我们为什么一定要那样做
It's such a beautiful day. Why do we have to do this?
因为这事办好了
Because when this thing is behind us,
就完事儿了 我们就没有后顾之忧了
It's done and we never have to think about it again.
来吧
Come on.
我上周六去了个葬礼 我就开始考虑
I went to a funeral last Saturday, and it got me thinking
我和歌洛莉亚死后的要葬在哪里
about where Gloria and I were gonna end up after we die.
可不是 这一周过得可真太有意思了
Yeah, it's been a fun week.
我不喜欢虎头蛇尾
I don't like loose ends.
所以我打了几个电话
So I made a few calls.
发现在有人在城里最好的墓地
I found these people selling a couple of primo plots
出售几块风水宝地
in the best cemetery in town.
并不是说我就快入土了
Not that I'm gonna go there anytime soon.
别那么肯定
Don't be so sure...
看看他平时吃的那些培根
with all the bacon that he eats.
行了 我吃降胆固醇的药
Well, got to give my cholesterol pills
总要有点用处吧
something to do.
我不管他们是怎么促销的
Mm. I don't care how much they promote it,
甘蓝是配菜
kale is a garnish.
无法独挑大梁的
It's not ready to anchor a meal.
看看这个
Look at this.
天啊 是我们在越南机场
Oh, my god! Lily's little hat
给莉莉买的小帽子
that we bought her at the airport in Vietnam.
还记得她戴着有多可爱吗
Remember how cute she looked in that?
还记得我还曾经戴着它走来走去
Remember how I used to wear it
表现出好像我有个巨大的脑袋吗
and walk around and act like I had a giant head?
你是实力派
Mm-hmm. That was good acting.
你在干什么
So, what are you doing?
我在将领养莉莉的过程
I'm putting together a little scrapbook
做成剪贴簿
of how Lily became ours.
她的领养证明
You know, her adoption certificate,
他们家那个村的几张照片
some pictures of her from her village --
全部开诚布公 这样她就不用觉得羞耻了
All out in the open, so she has nothing to be ashamed of.
你还想着这事儿呢
You leaving that on all day?
我还要写本小故事书
You know, and I'm also gonna write a little storybook --
我可以给她当睡前故事讲
you know, something I can read her at bedtime.
就叫"两只猴子和一只熊猫"
It's called "Two monkeys and a panda."
她是亚洲人 所以她是熊猫
She's the panda because she's Asian.
-我们是猴子是因为 -我只会画猴子
- And we're monkeys because... - I can draw monkeys.
我觉得这是个绝妙的计划
Okay, well, I think this is a great project,
我相信你一定会完成的
and I believe you are gonna finish it.
-天啊 -怎么了
- Oh, my god. - What?
莉莉的领养证明
Lily's adoption certificate.
-上面写的是莉莉·塔克·普里契特 -对
- Her name is "Lily Tucker Pritchett." - Right.
而不是"塔克-普里契特" 应该是这个才对
Not "Tucker-Pritchett" like it's supposed to be.
名"莉莉" 中间名"塔克"
First name -- "Lily." Middle name -- "Tucker."
姓"普里契特"
Last name -- "Pritchett."
那肯定不对啊
Well, that can't be right.
这可是法律文件
This is a legal document!
她冠的是你的姓
She only has your last name.
而我的姓就只是她的中间名
M-m-my name is just a middle name!
冷静 别难过
Stay calm. Don't get upset.
没有人会知道别人的中间名的
Nobody knows anyone's middle name!
-快问快答 我的中间名是什么 -斯考特
- Quick -- what's my middle name? - Scott.
你当然知道我的啦 我们可是一对
Of course you know mine. We're a couple!
这明显是弄错了
Okay, look, t-this is obviously a mistake.
但表格是你填的
But you're the one who filled out this paperwork.
你不会犯像这样的错误的
You don't make mistakes like this.
一般都是你来改正像这样的错误
You correct mistakes like this.
你是故意的
You did this on purpose.
什么
What?
你把我的名字藏起来
You buried my name,
你的姓就可以独霸鳌头
so your name could have top billing.
我才不要听你指责我
Okay, no, I am not gonnsit here and listen
做了这么过分的事情
to you accuse me of something so horrible!
现在全都说得通了
It makes so much sense now --
为什么所有法律文件你都想填
Why you wanted to fill out all these legal forms.
我是个律师
Okay, well, I'm a lawyer!
所以我填写所有法律文件
I fill out all the legal forms,
从你签了一个12年的健身会员开始就这样了
ever since you signed up for a 12-year gym membership!
会员时间越长 省的就越多
The more you spend, the more you save!
我所有的女同事都没时间去用那张温泉券
All the women I work with are too busy to use the certificate.
所以我给温泉那边打了电话
So I called the spa
希望他们能延长那张券的有效期
and asked them to extend the expiration date.
但他们拒绝了
But they said no.
真的要这样么
Really?
他们可真是打错算盘了
Here's something they didn't count on.
你和菲尔·邓菲过不去 你就要吃不了兜着走
You mess with Phil Dunphy, the claws come out.
你的手很好看
You have very nice hands.
像女人的手一样柔软
Soft like lady's.
谢谢你金 听你这么说我很高兴
Thank you, Kim. I appreciate that.
我妻子就好像从未注意过
My wife never seems to notice.
就这里了 嗒哒
This is it! Ta-da!
嗒哒什么
What is ta-da?
我就是说就在这里了 嗒哒
I'm just saying this is it. Ta-da.
"嗒哒"一般是当你按动了开关
"Ta-da" is when you do a flip
或者魔术师把个美女一切两半时说的
or where the magician cuts the pretty lady in half,
而不是当你给别人展示
not when you show someone
你想把他们的尸体塞进一个什么地方时说的话
where you want to shove their dead body.
我才不和你争论"嗒哒"的正确用法
I'm not gonna argue the proper use of "Ta-da."
就在这里了
This is it.
你认真的么 在这么一堆柜子里面吗
Seriously? In the file cabinet?
这叫教堂墓穴
It's called a crypt.
你怎么会不懂其中的妙处
And how are you not getting how great this is?
我们身处在豪情似海中的古堡中
We're four down from Bugsy siegel.
不 我才不要葬在有墙壁的地方
No. I'm not going into any wall.
我会长眠于地下
I'm going in the ground.
对不起 我才不要
Sorry, not me.
我才不要死后
There's enough to not like about death
还要和泥土和虫子相伴
without adding dirt and worms.
那会让我心里一阵阵发毛
The whole thing gives me the willies.
你死了 就应该被埋在地下
You die, you go to the ground.
这是自然法则 尘归尘 土归土
Is natural. You go back to the earth.
在这里 你就是一袋骨头
Here, you're just a mushy bag of bones
永远都在腐烂
rotting away for all eternity!
请您节哀
Sorry for your loss.
我们能赶紧从这出去了吗
Can we get the hell out of here?
我该和那个人怎么说
What am I supposed to tell the guy?
告诉他们我们才不希望在死后
Tell them we don't want our bodies
待在这样上帝无法找到我们的小抽屉里
inside these drawers where god cannot find us!
这和咱家的抽屉可不一样
These are not like our drawers at home.
人们可以在这些抽屉里面找到东西
People can find things in these.
我想弄个刘海
I'm thinking of getting bangs.
你绝对应该弄一个
Ooh, you totally should.
你要是有刘海 肯定很美
You would be so cute with bangs.
-你的脸型很适合留刘海 我就没有
- You have the face for it. I don't.
应该是我老婆
Oh, there's my better half.
金 介意帮我接一下吗
Kim, would you mind?
亲爱的 你在哪里
Hey, honey. Where are you?
我在去唐尼的路上
Oh, I'm on my way to Downey.
你知道吗
Oh, uh, did you know
卡伦和理查德·卡朋特夫妇是在唐尼长大的吗
Karen and richard carpenter grew up in Downey?
你说这事有意义吗 菲尔
What random and not-helpful fact, Phil.
对不起 我今天过得不太顺
I'm sorry. I'm -- I'm having kind of a rough day.
我过得也不是很顺利
Yeah, I'm kind of having a rough day myself.
菲尔 你得帮我做晚饭了
Look, Phil, I need you to take care of dinner for me.
怎么了
What's wrong?
艾莉克斯弄破了海莉的线衫
Oh, Alex ripped Haley's favorite sweater,
现在我就奔波在商店之间
and now I'm driving around from store to store,
试图在海莉发现之前给她再买件一模一样的
trying to find the exact same one before Haley finds out.
不用啊 跟她说一下发生了什么就行了
Don't do that. Just explain to her what happened.
不行 海莉不会理解的
Haley's not gonna understand.
-她当然会了 -不菲尔 你不明白
- Sure, she will. -- No, phil, you don't understand.
我只是想大事化小
I'm trying to avoid this turning into a whole big thing.
那就给她买件相似的就成啊
Then just get her something close.
她又看不出来
She'll never know the difference.
菲尔 就记住做晚饭好吗亲爱的
Phil, could you just take care of dinner, sweetie?
我就这么点要求 没了
That's all I'm asking. That's it.
我只是想说 有更简单的解决方式
I'm just saying, there's a simpler way to do this.
没什么更简单的方式 记得做饭
There is no simpler way. Just make dinner!
谢谢
Thank you.
喂
Hello?
怎么了
What?
普里契特先生
Mr. Pritchett...
我们是鲁特莱齐的人
We're the rutledges,
就是给你卖墓穴的人
the ones selling the spots.
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
天啊 看看亲爱的
Oh, my gosh. Look, honey.
我都没听说 马丁住进来了
I hadn't heard. Martin is in.
瞧瞧啊
Well, look at that.
-不好意思 那是你的朋友吗 -我们只是
- I'm sorry. Is that a friend of yours? - We've made a point
想认识"左邻右舍"的人而已
to get to know everyone in the neighborhood.
我们觉得 之后如果在那边遇见不会那么尴尬
We think it makes it less awkward, you know, later.
对不起 这位是我妻子 歌洛莉亚
Oh, I'm sorry. This is my wife, Gloria.
我是艾德 这里就是我的位置
I'm Ed, and this is my bunk.
这位是我可爱的妻子
And this is my loving wife
为三个孩子日夜操劳的母亲 维尼
and devoted mother of three, Winnie.
她会在这里
She'll be here.
我还不知道我们要怎么排
I don't know what our lineup is yet.
但在家的时候 我睡在右边
But at home,I sleep on the right side.
所以也许在那里
So probably there.
请恕我们无礼
We don't mean to be rude,
但你看起来好像比你丈夫年轻很多
but you seem to be much younger than your husband.
您不算无礼 我是年轻很多
You're not rude. I'm very much younger.
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
只是很有可能
Well, it's just that there's a good chance,
你会比她早很久进来
uh, you'll be moving in long before she would.
我们关心的是 一旦你妻子改嫁
Our concern is, your wife remarries,
而她想又和新丈夫葬在一起
and wants to be laid to rest with her new husband.
她就会把这个位置高价卖出
So she sells this spot to the highest bidder.
我们就要和一个陌生人做邻居了
And we're left lying next to a complete stranger,
甚至连个形式上的招呼都不会和我们打
without even so much as a formal "How do you do?"
歌洛莉亚 告诉他们你不会这样
Gloria, tell them you're in.
我不知道 杰 我觉得这确实是个问题
I don't know, Jay. I think they have a very good point.
而且他们一点也不荒唐
And they're not crazy at all.
你说这话是什么意思
What do you mean they have a good point?
我想我们不会选这里了
I don't think this is going to work.
希望你们能找到"新邻居"
Good luck getting someone into your drawers.
我觉得
It occurs to me
我可能有点过于不安了
that I may have gotten a little too upset
还得出了某些
and jumped to some conclusions
或许不正确的结论
that were perhaps not true.
我现在意识到
I realize now that you would
你绝对不会故意做出如此荒唐的事情
never intentionally do something so unthinkable.
所以
So...
我想说 我很抱歉 我指责了你
I just wanted to say I'm sorry for accusing you.
我确实做了
I did it.
我就知道 你个两面派
I knew it! You two-faced --
听我解释 那是
Let me explain. There is --
解释就是掩饰 掩饰就是一切罪恶的开始
There is no explanation. There is just no excuse.
我只想知道为什么
I just want to know why!
你知道吗 有些女人说
Okay, y-you know how, um, s-some women say
她们忘了生孩子有多痛苦
that they forget how painful childbirth was?
我想你是忘了
Well, I-I-I think that you are forgetting
在领养莉莉之前你有多惊慌失措
how panicked you were before we got Lily.
-你完全抓狂了 -我没有
- You were freaking out. - I was not!
这上面说床垫
Okay, so, it says that we can put the mattress
有三种不同的放法
at one of three different levels.
-我们应该选哪一个呢 -我不知道
- Which one should we do? - I don't know.
好吧 那想想我们应该把她放在多深的位置
Well, just think about how far down she should be.
-多深 -我不知道 我不能做这个
- How far -- - I don't know! I can't do this!
好的
Okay.
这个弹簧固定系统真是太棒了
Oh, this latch system is great.
真不知道以前的人是怎么固定的
What did people do before this?
我不知道 别问我问题
I don't know! Stop asking me questions!
-小卡 -我不能做这个 我不能
- Cam... - I can't do this! I can't!
好吧 我
Okay, well, I...
我可不觉得这两件事之间有什么联系
I don't see what that has to do with anything.
我很害怕这件事
I-I was scared that -- that it was just gonna all be
你承受不了 我怕你会离开我
too much for you and that you were gonna leave.
我就会成为一个单身爸爸
And then I would be the one taking care of a baby
带着的孩子还跟一个
and half of her last name
弃我而去的人姓
would belong to the guy who left us.
是我做错了 我很抱歉
It was a mistake. I'm sorry.
我本想挽回的
I-I wanted to have it changed,
但是我需要你的签名
but I needed to get your signature,
我怕这会让我们大吵一架
and I was afraid that it would start a big fight
会让你讨厌我 然后
and that you would hate me and...
那我就不明白了
OK, I'm confused.
你们是说 如果她告诉我她有了麻烦
You're saying that if she tells me she has a problem,
我却不该帮助她
I'm not supposed to help her?
除非她求你帮她
Not unless she asks for your help.
但如果她让我帮助她了
But if she lets me help her,
她就不会有麻烦了啊
I can make her problem go away.
那是你们男人的观点
That is such a male thing to say.
请原谅我是个男人
Well, forgive me for being a man.
芒果的还是猕猴桃的
Mango or kiwi?
猕猴桃的
Ooh, kiwi.
当你说应该如何如何做时
When you say, you know, "Do this or do that,"
她会觉得你是在说"我比你聪明多了"
all she's hearing is, "I'm smarter than you."
相信我 她不会这么想的
Believe me, she doesn't think that.
她不希望你替他解决麻烦
She doesn't want you to save her problems.
她只希望得到你的支持
She just wants you to give her support
让她自己解决麻烦
so that she can solve her problems herself.
没错 而且有时候
Yes, and sometimes --
有时候她只需要一个倾诉的对象
sometimes she just wants a sympathetic ear.
或许这才问题的关键
Maybe it's all the creams,
但说的很有道理 姑娘们
but that just made sense, girlfriends.
那么如果克莱尔说 我讨厌堵车
So if Claire says, "I hate getting stuck in traffic,"
-我就不该说 你应该早点出门 -不
- I shouldn't say, "Maybe you should leave earlier"... - No.
-或是 别上高速公路 -不
- ...Or, "Don't get on the freeway." - No.
我应该说 我懂 这是挺郁闷的
I should just say, "I know. It's so frustrating."
-是的 这就对了 -真的吗
- Yes! That's it! - Really?
没错
Yes! Yes!
如果她说
And -- and if she says, uh, uh...
今天的服务员态度太差了
"The waiter I had today was so rude,"
我不该说 你应该一次性
I shouldn'say, "Maybe you should just order
-把菜全点好 -不行
- something on the menu for once." - No.
我应该说 真混蛋
I should just say, "What a jerk."
对了 就是这样
Yes! Yes! Yeah!
如果她说 菲尔 这节目快把我逼疯了
And if she says, "Phil, the TV's driving me crazy,"
我应该说 我知道
I should just say, "I know!
现在的电视节目都不是人看的
There is not enough quality programming for men."
不 你应该关掉那该死的电视
No! Turn off the damn TV.
好吧 我又不明白了
Okay, now I'm confused again.
听说你今天过的不太愉快啊
So, I heard you had a rough time today.
是啊
Yeah, well...
还记得那些我们以为会永远在一起的日子吗
Remember the days when we thought we'd live forever?
你想去玩吗
Don't you want to go play?
我什么时候玩过
When do I ever play?
我似乎也得应付
I'm kind of wrestling
这些老夫少妻的事
with this whole "older man, younger woman" thing.
就好像我和克罗伊的生活背景不同
It's like Chloe and I grew up in different worlds.
今天我说了个关于威格尔家的笑话
Today I made a joke about the Wiggles.
-她居然一头雾水 -我不知道你说的什么
- It went right over her head. - I don't know what that is.
这是个短语 意思就是她不明白
It's an expression -- means she didn't get it.
是啊 有时候年龄的事
Yeah, it sometimes -- this age thing --
是很让人心烦
knocks you in the head.
你是指什么呢
That what this is about?
我一直都明白 我去世之后你妈可能会改嫁
I always knew your mother might remarry after I'm gone.
可我从来没烦恼过
That never bothered me.
她嫁过你爸 嫁过我
I figured her husbands would be your dad, me,
肯定也会嫁某些完全比不上我的傻瓜
and some putz who could never live up to me.
但如果我不是她心中最重要的那一个怎么办
But what if I'm not the main guy?
如果她更爱其他人
What if some other guy is?
如果我才是那个傻瓜
What if I'm the putz?
我妈和我爸离婚的时候
When my mom and dad got divorced,
你知道有多少人在追求她吗
do you have any idea how many guys chased after her?
电话铃声就没停过
The phone didn't stop ringing.
那些人会半路把她拦住
Men would stop her on the street.
车还没停下 就向她求婚
Guys would propose to her from moving cars.
他们都长得很帅 又多金
They were good-looking guys, Jay -- with money.
我觉得他们中的一个能当总统
I think one of them was a Kennedy.
你说这些是什么意思
Where are you going with this?
当你出现的时候 我觉得你没什么希望
When you showed up, I didn't think you had a prayer.
你紧张得大汗淋漓的 我真为感到难过
You were so nervous and sweaty, I felt sorry for you.
我可是被迫爬了三段楼梯
I had to climb three flights of stairs.
但在所有人中 我妈选中了你
But of all people, my mom fell for you.
她追姑娘很有一手
I got a few moves.
她说第一次和你吵架的时候就爱上你了
She said she fell in love with you during your first fight.
-什么 -她说她终于找到了真命天子
- What? - She said she'd finally met her match.
是嘛
Oh.
所以如果你认为她会在你去世后
So if you think she's just gonna replace you
找人代替你
when you're gone,
那你就是个傻瓜
Then you are the putz.
谢谢你 孩子 醍醐灌顶啊
Thanks, kid.I appreciate that.
我还以为一开始你就喜欢我
I thought you liked me when I first showed up.
拜托 头一个月
Please. For the first month,
我甚至都不想知道你的名字
I didn't even bother to learn your name.
-她回来了吗 -在路上了
- Is she back yet? - She's on her way.
-你找到了吗 -找到了
- Did you find it? - I did.
终于在第五家店找到了
At the fifth store I went to.
就在橱窗里 我是从模特身上扒下来的
It was in the window, and I had to undress a mannequin
还被一个变态拍了下来
while a creepy guy filmed it,
我们估计能在网上找到
So we have to look forward to on the internet.
-太谢谢你了 妈妈 -不谢
- Thank you so much, mom. - You're welcome.
现在 快放到它原来的地方去 知道吗
Now, go put that exactly where you found the other one, okay?
好的
Okay.
啊欧
Uh-oh.
-什么 -防盗扣还在上面呢
- What? The security tag -- it's still on!
我跟他们说了让他们取下来
I told those people to take that off.
-不 -她已经开入停车道了
- Oh, no. - She's pulling into the driveway!
好的 没事 没事
Okay. It's fine. It's fine.
别紧张 快弄好了 快弄好了
Don't panic. I've got it. I've got it.
-她下车了 -别闹了 我正在弄
- She's getting out of the car! - All right! I am doing it!
快弄好了 我 哦 天啊 糟了
I've almost got it. I -- oh, god! Oh, no!
-什么东西 -是墨水
- What is that?! - Well, it's ink.
藏起来 快藏起来
Aah! Hide it. Hide it.
-她进来了 -你把我毛衣怎么了
- She's in the house! - What are you doing with my sweater?
天啊 你把它毁了
Oh, my god! It's ruined!
只是个意外
It was an accident!
我就知道会这样 你个笨蛋
I knew this would happen, you idiot!
嘿 嘿 有话好好说
Hey, hey! Let's try to get along.
我真希望她根本没生下来过
I wish she was never even born!
他们只不过需要一个有脑子的孩子
They were trying to make one with a brain!
别乱讲 亲爱的 你们都很
Not fair! Honey, you guys are both...
都很聪明
Oh...pretty smart.
噢
Ohh...
天啊
Geez.
是线衫的事对吧
It's that sweater, huh?
对 就是线衫的事
Yeah. It is that sweater.
我尽了一切努力避免她们吵架
And I did everything I can to stop them from fighting.
我就不懂了
I don't understand.
她们怎么没意识到你有多么爱她们
Why they can't see how much you love them.
我也不懂
I don't know.
还有今天绮丽儿一直给我打电话
Meanwhile, Cheryl has be calling me all day
就因为她生气我没去
because she's angry I didn't show up.
绮丽儿家里不是有管家和保姆什么的吗
Doesn't Cheryl have a housekeeper and a nanny?
为什么她还要别人帮忙
Why does she need so much help?
我也知道 你说是吧
I know, right?
你鞠躬尽瘁
You work so hard.
你劳苦功高
You do so much.
对啊
I do.
百分之百对
Of course you do.
确实
I do.
亲爱的 谢谢你
Oh, sweetie, thank you.
真的很感谢
I really appreciate that.
嘿
Hey.
什么
Yeah?
我老婆是谁
Who's my gal?
就是我
I am.
答对了 就是你
Darn right. Yeah.
我去洗个手
Oh. Let me get this.
嘿 还有一件事
Hey, by the way --
发现我有什么不同吗
notice anything different about me?
没啊
Unh-unh.
哈
Huh.
哪里不同了
Hmm. What is it?
没什么
Nothing.
-剪头发了吗 -一个礼拜前就剪了
- A haircut? - A week ago.
好啦 快点告诉我
Okay, so, tell me.
算了 没什么重要的
Forget it. It's not important.
我去做饭了
Okay. I'll just go start dinner.
听着 我想了想
Listen, I've been thinking.
在我死了以后
When I go,
我想告诉你
I want you to know...
你嫁给别人也可以的
It's okay if you marry someone else.
我知道
I know.
因为我想你幸福
Because I want you be happy.
我会幸福的
I'll be happy.
你故意气我是不是
You're driving me crazy on purpose, right?
杰 我不会嫁给别人的
Jay, I'm not going to marry anyone else.
你现在是这么说的
That's what you say now,
但是没人知道未来是怎样的
but no one knows what the future holds.
所以我给你这个
So I want you to have this.
看这个
Look at this,
一个空的咖啡罐
an empty coffee can.
你知道追我的男人给我买什么吗
Do you know what men used to buy me?
我死了以后 把我火化了
When I go, toss me in the fire,
把我的骨灰放进这个罐子里面
Sweep up my ashes, stick 'em in that.
嗒哒
Ta-da!
我得跟你谈一谈这个"嗒哒"
We need to talk about this "Ta-da."
因为我不在乎我死后待的地方有没有墙
'Cause I don't care if it's in a wall
或者还是被深埋地下
or if it's in the ground --
我只要和你在一起就行了
just as long as I end up with you.
哦 杰
Oh, Jay.
太完美了
It's perfect.
杰·普里契特的骨灰咖啡罐放在壁橱上
Jay Pritchett sitting on the mantel in the old coffee can.
这些追求者就傻眼了 我就喜欢这样
That will drive the putz crazy. And I like that.
所以说 我左思右想
Um, so, f-for whatever it's worth,
我还是叫来了收养律师
I-I called the adoption attorney --
收养 耶
Adoption, yay!
在星期一 他们就会开始着手准备
And on Monday, they're gonna start the process
把莉莉的姓改成塔克-普里契特
of changing lily's last name to "Tucker-pritchett."
好啊
Great.
我想再次道歉
Again, I'm -- I'm so sorry.
好吧
Okay.
这个 我
Um... Oh, I, uh...
我刚写完了《两只猴和一只熊猫》
I took a quick pass at "Two Monkeys and a Panda."
我想听听你的看法
So, just let me know what you think.
"很久很久以前
"Once upon a time,
有两只猴子
there were two monkeys.
他们都很爱对方
They loved each other very much,
但是还是缺少一样东西
but there was something missing."
连字号吗
A hyphen?
"他们想要一个孩子
"They wanted a baby.
他们听说在遥远的地方有一个特别的孩子
And they heard that there was a very special baby
她需要一个家
in a faraway land who needed a family.
她是一只熊猫 名字叫莉莉
She was a panda named Lily.
其中一只猴子惊慌失措
One of the monkeys was scared.
他们从未养过熊猫孩子
They'd never had a panda before.
但是在他们把莉莉抱在怀里的时候
But they held Lily in their arms,
那只惊慌失措的猴子变得勇敢了
and the scared monkey became the brave one.
这两只猴子
And the two monkeys --"
-可可和米克 -不好意思 你说什么
- Coco and Miko. - I'm sorry. What?
可可和米克是两只猴子的名字
"Coco" And "Miko" Are the names of the monkeys.
是吗
Really?
听起来有那么一点
That doesn't seem like it's a little un--
可可和米克 我喜欢 我喜欢
Coco and Miko. I like that. I like that.
可可和米克 对
Coco and Miko -- yeah.
"他们带上他们收养的完美的小熊猫
"They traveled all the way home
回到了家里
with the perfect panda that they adopted."
她刚刚是不是拍手了
Did she just clap?
她听到"收养"就拍手了
She heard "Adopted" And clapped!
小卡 这太不可思议了
Cam! That's amazing!
哦 天啊 你做到了
Oh, my god! You did that!
-那个 我没有 -什么
- Well, I don't... - What?!
你做到了 难以置信 我不敢相信
You did that. That is amazing. I can't believe that.
就像这样 和平回到了家里
And just like that, peace returned to our house.
理论上来说 这是我的家 但是
Well, technically, I-it's my house, but...
我 我马上就去改了
I-I will -- I will fix that, too.
当我们把书写完的时候
Once we finished writing the book,
我们发现一件事情
we realized something.
不仅仅是我们这两只猴子有熊猫宝宝
We're not the only two monkeys with the panda,
同性恋夫妇是一个巨大的市场
gay parents are a huge market,
没人专门给他们写书
and no one's writing for them.
我觉得我们简直是坐拥金矿
We thought we were sitting on a gold mine.
可惜不是
But we weren't.
《同性恋养孩子》
"Gay Parenting."
-《同性恋收养孩子》 -好吧
- "Gay Adoptive Parenting." - Okay.
-《同性恋收养外国孩子》 -哇哦
"Gay Adoption: Foreign Children." Wow.
-《同性恋收养亚裔孩子》 -虾米
- "Gay Adoption: Asian Children." - What?
-《双性恋收养亚洲孩子》
- "Bisexual Adoption: Asian Children."
-《变性人收养孩子》
- "Transgendered Adoption."
够了 米克我们走
Okay, come on. Let's go, Miko.